RESUME

Pramod Maruti Fage (System Administrator)

Mobile No: 9637520506

Email: pramod.fage@hotmail.com

Objective

A place where I can implement my skills to contribute towards the growth of the organization. Seeking a challenging position that involves creativity and my interpersonal skills are best utilized and enhanced. Where I can get an exposure to the most advanced technologies in use today and working against strong deadlines to improve my productivity and made me worthy of every coin I learn.

Summary

Having 10 years of experience in the field of Information Technology where Planning, Implementation, Administration and Troubleshooting are involved with many platforms of OS like Microsoft Windows 2008, 2012, 2016 and 2019 and VMware Virtualization ESXi 7.0 vSphere and vCenter Server.

Professional Experience

Marlow Navigation India Pvt. Ltd. Mumbai from July - 2021 to till date as a System Administrator.

Work Responsibility

- Troubleshooting Amos Connect (EMS), Oracle Crewing Database connectivity issues.
- Hands-on experience in designing & implementing IT Policies, Procedures, IT Infrastructure & security management.
- Installing and configuring all the DNV Navigator server/client programs for onboard and offshore.
- Configuring business and crew LAN network in Infinity firewall for vessel network.
- Configuring and installing the Infinity Firewall on Vessel like Failover, port forwarding, Allow and deny rules, content filtering, activating user account for Wifi, creating group and quota of the vessel etc.
- Installation and Configuration of Citrix Receiver and workspace program.
- ❖ Managing regular backup of server and user data in tape or HDD using Veritas Backup Exec 16.
- Vessel IT onsite support (Vessel visit as an IT technician globally) and offsite support (on email and telephone call).
- Installing and configuring Microsoft office 365 program Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook Email, One Note, Access etc.
- ❖ Administration of the Microsoft Office 365 to manage emails and licenses.
- ❖ Updating AMC needs for IT Infrastructure and maintain AMC records.
- Managing hardware assets (Computers, Mobiles, Data Cards, Printers and Scanner).
- ❖ Administration of VMware ESXI Host and VCSA 7.0.
- Upgradation and Update Installation of vCenter Server Appliance and creating Virtual Machines.
- Assist in P2V conversion of Windows server editions using enterprise VMware converter and also installed the VMware tools on those machines.
- Provided disaster recovery and backup services using the VMware consolidated Backup (VCB).
- Creating templates and deploying Virtual Machines through templates, cloning Virtual Machines and managing VCenter permissions.
- Creating and Managing VMware cluster with HA and DRS.
- Creating and Managing resource pools for Virtual Machines.
- Monitoring and managing performance of ESXI servers and Virtual Machines.
- Using vCenter Server Appliance for HA, DRS and VMotion.
- Working on Migration concepts like VMotion and cold migration.

- Troubleshooting of Virtual Network.
- Troubleshooting ESXI Virtual Machines.
- Assists in the evaluation, recommends negotiations and contracts for the purchases of system software products.
- Performs technical analysis, installation, maintenance and modification of operating system software.
- Troubleshoots and resolves problems and monitors system performance while simultaneously support staff engaged in similar efforts.

Worked with NEWTRONIC LIFECARE EQUIPEMENT PVT. LTD. Mumbai from November – 2016 to 30th June 2021 as a System Administrator. Work Responsibility

- System monitoring
- ❖ New accounts set-up and active directory administration
- Design new computer systems system and server performance
- * Run reports on system performance for team and wider organization
- Optimize processes and lead process improvement
- ❖ Manage staff and user credentials and frameworks
- Manage and fulfil branches IT requirements.
- Troubleshoot technical issues
- Create and implement training for staff
- ❖ Coordinate and provide support for Firewall and network system
- Ensure systems are secure and protected from breach or viruses
- Monitoring and maintaining network servers such as file servers, VPN gateways and intrusion detection systems.
- ❖ Managing and maintaining G Suit email Services.
- ❖ Ensuring high-level security and efficiency resulting in 100% output.

Worked with ITV COMPUTERS PVT LTD. Mumbai from May – 2014 to July 2016 as a Sr. Technical Support Engineer.

Work Responsibility

- ❖ Administering Active directory (AD) on Windows 2003 and windows 8 servers, created users, groups using group policy.
- ❖ Installation of switches, routers and other networking hardware,
- ❖ Responsibilities Installing LAN, WAN, operating systems like Win2000Server/Win2003Server/2008Server Professional, Win XP, Win NT, 98, windows 7 and Windows 8 as per the requirement of the client.
- ❖ Daily operations Remotely Maintain all Servers, User Calls like Desktop level calls, Software related call Network related calls.
- Hardware, Application, operating system, Network and Printer level calls
- Managing technical support team which is responsible for infrastructure services on Microsoft Windows technology
- ❖ Installed software patching, upgrading and maintenance of operating system.
- Installed, upgraded and maintenance of server hardware components as per requirement.
- Installed complex hardware, software, and upgrades to ensure work is performed as per the company policy.
- Created and implemented recommendations to improve scalability and performance.
- Creating standard server build
- Updating servers with latest service packs and hot fixes
- ❖ Implementing Cyberoam Firewall creating rules for user blocking harmful sites and allow the recommended sites for the user and load balancing of traffic.
- ❖ Handling MS Outlook, Outlook Express related problems and PST backup.
- * Remote Desktop facilities providing to the side offices as per their requirement.
- Preparing monthly work status report and updating technology specific documents.
- Providing Antivirus related support to the various Client and handling corporate versions of antivirus.
- ❖ Installation and maintenance of all Tata Reliance Wireless data card broadband and solved all Issues.

Worked with Ruchi Infosytems Corporation (RIC Group) Mumbai from May -2012 to May 2014 Technical Support Engineer.

Work Responsibility

- Troubleshooting client server problem.
- ❖ Configure DHCP, DNS, and Domain in windows server 2003 and 2008.
- Outlook configuration and troubleshooting.
- Outlook backup & Restoration.
- Network troubleshooting.
- ❖ Installation of ADSL Router & Wireless Access Point.
- Troubleshooting internet problems.
- Desktop Installation.
- Configure Local & Network Print Devices.
- ❖ Tally Installation, Tally Backup and troubleshooting of technical problem in tally.
- Software installation (Photoshop, Corel Draw, MS Office 2003, 2007, 2010, Auto Cad)
- Software upgrades.
- **❖** Data recovery.
- ❖ Antivirus installation, activation and update.
- Configure new hardware, install and update the software packages.
- Create and maintain computer networks.
- ❖ Maintain and update inventory of all hardware and software.
- Operating System (OS) installation upgrades and patches for laptop, desktop and server.

Highlights of IT Skills

VMware Infrastructure Skills:

- ❖ Managing VMware infrastructure environment with vCSA, ESXi servers, virtual machines.
- ❖ VM Servers build & rebuild (Deploying the New VM from the Template and Cloning an Existing VM) as per the client request through change management process.
- Installing and configuring ESXi servers.
- Installing, configuring and managing virtual infrastructure and virtual center server.
- Creating and managing resource pools and adding the VM's into resource pools.
- Creating and managing virtual machines and installing VM Tools into VM's.
- ❖ Manage VM's using VMware virtual center server.
- ❖ Managing VM's through web access.
- ❖ Installation and configuration of virtual machines in an Enterprise SAN environment.
- Security hardening and Monitoring of VM's & ESXi servers (CPU, Memory, Disk, Network Utilization) for Security Compliance.
- Configurations of Virtual switches and network connections.
- Performing Snapshots, Cloning, cold migrations and hot migrations.
- Creating templates from VM's and deploy VM's from templates and allocate resources.
- Creating duplicate VM's using cloning.
- ❖ Moving VM's from one VMFS Data store to another VMFS Data store using Storage VMotion.
- Manage users, groups, permissions and roles.
- * Regular System Administration tasks like User Accounts, access, Permissions, Security, Planning.

Administration of Windows and Windows Server Skills:

- ❖ Installation, configuration and administration of Windows Server 2008 R2, Windows Server 2012 R2 and Standard, Windows Server 2016 Standard, Windows Server 2019 Standard Servers.
- ❖ Installation, configuration and administration of Windows 7 Professional Client OS.
- ❖ Installing and configuring DHCP, DNS and Active Directory.
- * Responsible for server deployments, which include application installations, operating system updates and security patches.
- Handling Desktop Management including Home Directory, Profiles, and Folder Redirection.
- Configuration Network Printers.
- Maintaining Anti-Virus Server.
- Creating and Managing User accounts.

- Knowledge of MS Outlook, Outlook Express Clients.
- Troubleshooting LAN Connectivity related problems.
- ❖ Taking Back ups and Troubleshooting Systems.
- Assigning Folder Permissions to users.
- Maintaining Assets Inventory and documentation.

Network Skills:

- Installing and Configuring firewall (Sophos, Fortinet).
- ❖ Configuration of Mail Server (POSTMASTER/HMAILSERVER/G Suit).
- ❖ Cabling & crimping for systems, switches & Routers.
- OSI Layers.
- Topologies.
- ❖ IP Addressing.
- Good networking / Internet fundamentals.
- ❖ Installation & configuration of LAN.
- ❖ Knowledge of Door Access, CCTV and Biometric Attendance Systems

Academic Qualification

BCom from Mumbai University HSC from Maharashtra Board SSC from Maharashtra Board

Technical Qualification

Successfully completed VMware vSphere: Install, Configure, Manage [V7.0] from Attari Classes Learning Center Kurla (West) Mumbai.

Successfully completed the Computer Hardware & Networking Course from Jetking Infotrain Limited, Borivali Learning Centre in Jan 2012.

JCHNP (Jetking Certified Hardware & Networking Professional). Studied Jetking Certified CCNA, Networking Essential and Basic Electronics.

Personal Details

Name Pramod Maruti Fage. 13th March 1990 Date of Birth

Address A/104, Sanskruti Height, Phase I, Sector V,

Near Railway Yard, Nile More, Nallasopara (W) 401203

Nationality Indian Gender Male Marital Status Married

Languages Known English, Marathi, and Hindi

Place

Date

I hereby declare that the above-furnished details are true to the best of my knowledge. If given chance to work with your esteemed corporation, I assure you, to give my 100% and believe to be fruitful to your organization.

Your Faithfully

Pramod M Fage.